Guide to the International Platform Association records, 1904-2001 MS2273
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Platform Association records
1904-2001
1940-1990
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Moore, Dan Tyler
Schaeffer, Jean
Anderson, Jack
Owens, Luvie
Pearson, Drew, 1897-1969
MS2273
50.5 Linear Feet
The International Platform Association was an organization that functioned between 1831 and 2001. The organization began as the American Lyceum Association, and served as a means for people to debate and voice their oppinions in a public setting. In the early years that followed, organizations all across the country began establishing their own lyceums; by 1834, there were several thousand. Thousands of people came to sessions to hear lectures made by eminent politicians, artists, and scientists. This collection contains office correspondence, publications of International Lyceum Association and International Platform Association, convention photographs, convention audiotape cassettes, convention videotape cassettes.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains office correspondence, publications of the International Lyceum Association and the International Platform Association, convention photographs, convention audiotape cassettes, and convention videotape cassettes. The material dates from 1904-2001. In addition to general correspondence, publications, photographs, and audiovisual material, the collection also contains files that were maintained by Dan Tyler Moore, Jr. and Jean Schaeffer.
Arrangement
Organized into 7 series: Governance, 1930-1990, Correspondence, 1940-1992, Publications, 1904-1978, Dan Moore's files, 1950-1960, Jean Schaeffer's files, 1978-1992, Photographs, 1962-1986, and Audiovisual, 1977-2001.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the International Platform Association/Mark Rhoades, 2009 (Accession 2009.036)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical / Historical
The International Platform Association was an organization that functioned between 1831 and 2001. The organization began as the American Lyceum Association, and served as a means for people to debate and voice their oppinions in a public setting. In the early years that followed, organizations all across the country began establishing their own lyceums; by 1834, there were several thousand. The Chautauqua Movement grew out of the American Lyceum Association. This was established at Lake Chautauqua, New York, and offered adult education in both science and the humanities. Thousands of people came to sessions to hear lectures made by eminent politicians, artists, and scientists. In 1902, the International Lyceum Association was established and existed until 2001. The association organized to "dedicate itself to the improvement of the lecture, concert, and entertainment fields, to maintain the highest standard of presentations, to increase the welfare of those engaged therein, and to foster and develop goodwill and fellowship among its members." The organization changed its name to the International Platform Assocaition in 1947.
Lectures and lecturing.; Elocution.; Elocutionists; International Platform Association; Chautauquas
- Governance, 1920-1990; Series 1; 1.5 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  The materials of this series include minutes, ledgers, receipts, bylaws, and a copy of the International Platform Association's amended constitution. They range in date from 1920 to 1990.
  Arrangement
  Arranged in no particular order.
  - Governance, circa 1920-1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Flat box 1)
    General
    This series consists of one flatbox containing the amended constitution of the IPA, meeting minutes, ledgers, invoices, and receipts.
- Correspondence, 1940-1960; Series 2; 9 Linear Feet
  Arranged alphabetically by name of recipient.
  The series primarily contains correspondence related to the logisitics and funding of the International Platform Association's annual meetings. The material ranges in date from 1940-1992.
  - [Correspondence - A], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - [Correspondence - A], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - [Correspondence - B], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - [Correspondence - B], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - [Correspondence - B], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - [Correspondence - C], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - [Correspondence - C], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - [Correspondence - D], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - [Correspondence - D], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - [Correspondence - E], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - [Correspondence - F], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - [Correspondence - F], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - [Correspondence - G], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - [Correspondence - G], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - [Correspondence - H], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - [Correspondence - H], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - [Correspondence - J], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - [Correspondence - K], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - [Correspondence - K], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - [Correspondence - L], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - [Correspondence - L], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - [Correspondence - L], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - [Correspondence - M], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - [Correspondence - M], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - [Correspondence - M], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - [Correspondence - M], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - [Correspondence - M], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - [Correspondence - N], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - [Correspondence - O], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - [Correspondence - P], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - [Correspondence - P], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - [Correspondence - P], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - [Correspondence - Q], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - [Correspondence - R], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - [Correspondence - R], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - [Correspondence - R], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - [Correspondence - R], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - [Correspondence - R], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - [Correspondence - S], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - [Correspondence - S], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - [Correspondence - S], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - [Correspondence - S], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - [Correspondence - S], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - [Correspondence - S], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - [Correspondence - S], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - [Correspondence - S], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - [Correspondence - S], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - [Correspondence - T], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - [Correspondence - U], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - [Correspondence - V], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - [Correspondence - W], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - [Correspondence - X,Y,Z], circa 1940-1960; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Publications, 1904-1978; Series 3; 10.5 Linear Feet
  Arranged alphabetically by name of publication and chronologically within each publication.
  The materials of this series include multiple different publications produced by the International Platform Association as well as newspaper articles related to the organization. Publications include The Lakeside Bulletin, The Lyceum Magazine, The Lyceumite, The Lyceumite and Talent, The National Community, The Platform, The Platform World, Program, Programming, Talent, and Talent of the Platform World. Materials also include newsletters, postcards, programs, and yearbooks. The materials range in date from 1904 to 1978.
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1913 June-September; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1913 October-December; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1914 January-April; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1914 May-November; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1915 March-July; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1915 August-September; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1915 October-December; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1918 June-November; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1919 February-December; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1920 March-December; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1921 January-June; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1921 July-November; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1922 April-September; Series 3 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1916-1918; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1916-1918; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1916-1918; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1916-1918; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1916-1918; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1916-1918; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1922-1925; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1922-1925; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1922-1925; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1922-1925; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1922-1925; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1922-1925; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1922-1925; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1925-1928; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1925-1928; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1925-1928; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1925-1928; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1925-1928; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - The Lyceum Magazine, 1925-1928; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - The Lyceumite, 1904 January-May; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - The Lyceumite, 1904 August-December; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - The Lyceumite, 1905 January-May; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Lyceumite, 1905 June-November; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - The Lyceumite, 1906 January-July; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The Lyceumite, 1906 October-December; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - The Lyceumite, 1907 February-April; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - The Lyceumite and Talent, 1907 July-November; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - The Lyceumite and Talent, 1908 March-December; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The Lyceumite and Talent, 1909 January-December; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - The Lyceumite and Talent, 1910 February-June; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - The Lyceumite and Talent, 1911 March-July; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The Lyceumite and Talent, 1911 August-November; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - The Lyceumite and Talent, 1912 February-July; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - The Lyceumite and Talent, 1912 August-December; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The Lyceumite and Talent, 1913 January-May; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Programs, Newsletters, and Directories, 1956-1961; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Program, 1955-1969; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Program, 1973-1977; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Programming Magazine, 1975-1978; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - The Platform World, 1929; Series 3 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - The Platform World, 1930 January-June; Series 3 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - The Platform World, 1930 July-December; Series 3 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - The Platform World, 1931; Series 3 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - The Platform World, 1932-1954; Series 3 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - [Convention Programs], 1986-1998; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - [Yearbooks and Directories], 1912-1914; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - [Yearbooks and Directories], 1917-1918; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - [Yearbooks and Directories], 1919-1920; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - [Yearbooks and Directories], 1923-1924; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - [Yearbooks and Directories], 1927-1957; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - [Yearbooks and Directories], 1965; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - [Scrapbook], circa 1960-1980; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - [Scrapbooks], 1945-1989; Series 3 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Talent, 1904 April-December; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Talent, 1905 January-April; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Talent, 1905 May-December; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Talent, 1906 March-August; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Talent, 1906 September-December; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Talent, 1907 January-May; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Talent, 1935-1939; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Talent, 1940-1943; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Talent, 1944-1946; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Talent, 1947; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Talent, 1948; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Talent, 1949; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Talent, 1950; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Talent, 1951; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Talent, 1952; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Talent, 1953; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Talent, 1955-1962; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Talent, 1963-1965; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Talent, 1967-1969; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Talent, 1970-1971; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Talent, 1972; Series 3 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Talent, 1973; Series 3 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Talent, 1974-1975; Series 3 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Talent, 1976-1978; Series 3 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Talent, 1979-1981; Series 3 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Talent, 1982-1984; Series 3 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Talent, 1985-1990; Series 3 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Talent, 1992-1998; Series 3 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - [Talent flyers], circa 1920-1930; Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - [Talent flyers], circa 1920-1930; Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - [Talent flyers], circa 1920-1930; Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - [Talent flyers], circa 1920-1930; Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - [Talent flyers], circa 1920-1930; Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - [Talent flyers], circa 1920-1930; Series 3 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - [Talent flyers], circa 1920-1930; Series 3 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - [Talent flyers], circa 1920-1930; Series 3 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - [Talent flyers], circa 1920-1930; Series 3 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- Dan Moore's Files, 1950-1960; Series 4; 3.5 Linear Feet
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  This series contains the personal files of Dan Tyler Moore that are related to the International Platform Association. Dan Tyler Moore was the organization's executive director for several decades. The series includes correspondence, news clippings, flyers, photographs, programs, transcripts of speeches, and copies of various publications of the International Platform Association. The materials range in date from 1950 to 1960.
  - Bob Leiman Group III, 1990; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Braff, P.J., 1952; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Brandywine Precision Company, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - George H. Bender, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Bid abstracts, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Bids forwarded, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - City Blue Printing, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Cleveland Chamber of Commerce, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Cleveland Electric Motor Company, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Cleveland Electronics, Inc., circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Cleveland Engineering Company, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Cleveland Ordnance District, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - [Columbus Lite], circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Commerce Clearing House, Inc., circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - [Correspondence - C.E. Backman], circa 1950-1970; Series 4 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Coleman Peterson Company, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Contract file, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Corwin, Robert K., 1951; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Cosmo Plastics Company, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Covington and Burling, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Cowan Construction Co. Shawnee, Oklahoma, 1951; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Cowles, D.L., 1957; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Creative Programming Institute, 1974; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Creative Programming Institute, 1975; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Dan Moore photos, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Donations in Dan's name, 1998; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Florida trip 1989, Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - House, circa 1980-2000; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - IPA - Leiman Bowl Award (Parliamentary), circa 1980-1990; Series 4 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Leiman, Bob, 1975; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Leiman, Bob, 1979; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Lists of speakers, circa 1970-1980; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - [Loose papers], circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - [Loose papers], circa 1970-1980; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - [Loose papers 1 of 4], circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - [Loose papers 2 of 4], circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - [Loose papers 3 of 4], circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - [Loose papers 4 of 4], circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Market place of the lecture platform, 1986; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Market place of the lecture platform, 1988; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Meeting management seminar, 1978; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Membership, circa 1970-1980; Series 4 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - National Lecture Management, Inc., circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - National Lecture Management, Inc., 1952-1953; Series 4 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - National Lecture Management, 1953; Series 4 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Redpath Backman Chicago, 1960; Series 4 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - [Redpath Bureau], circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Redpath-Higgins, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - School Assembly Service, circa 1955-1965; Series 4 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Speeches, 1959; Series 4 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Speeches, 1960; Series 4 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Speeches, 1962; Series 4 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Stewart-Edna Celebrity Management, Inc., circa 1960-1970; Series 4 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - When the Chautauquas Folded, circa 1950-1960; Series 4 (Box 37, Folder 3)
- Jean Schaeffer's Files, 1950-1992; Series 5; 1 Linear Feet
  Arranged in the order by the creator.
  This series contains the personal files of Jean Schaeffer that are related to the International Platform Association. The series includes a copy of the International Platerform Association's constitution and bylaws, correspondence, form letters, notes, programs, and copies of the publication Talent. The materials range in date from 1950 to 1992.
  - Constitution and by-laws, 1956; Series 5 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Fabray, Nanette, 1989-1990; Series 5 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Form letters and notes, circa 1950-1960; Series 5 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - IPA 1978, Series 5 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - IPA 1979, Series 5 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - IPA 1980, Series 5 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - IPA 1981, Series 5 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - IPA 1982, Series 5 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - IPA 1983, Series 5 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - IPA 1984, Series 5 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - IPA 1985, Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - IPA 1986, Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - IPA 1987, Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - IPA 1988, Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - IPA 1989, Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - IPA 1990, Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - IPA 1991, Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - IPA 1992, Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Talent - Miscellaneous information, circa 1980-1985; Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - [Loose papers], circa 1950-1990; Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Rev. Alfred W. Stone estate, circa 1980-1982; Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Talent Magazine - permission to reprint, circa 1960-1980; Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Young America Oratorical Superbowl, circa 1975-1985; Series 5 (Box 39, Folder 13)
- Photographs, 1962-1995; Series 6; 14.5 Linear Feet
  The materials in this series predominantly consist of photographs from International Platform Association conventions. There are also a number of unidentified photographs. Materials include both color and black and white photographs in various sizes. The materials range in date from 1962 to 1995.
  Arranged in the order in which it was received.
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1975-1985; Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1975-1985; Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1975-1985; Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1975-1985; Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1975-1985; Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1975-1985; Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1975-1985; Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1975-1985; Series 6 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1975-1985; Series 6 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1980-1990; Series 6 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1980-1990; Series 6 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1985-1995; Series 6 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1985-1995; Series 6 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1985-1995; Series 6 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - [Photographs of conventions], circa 1985-1995; Series 6 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - [Photographs of convention], 1979; Series 6 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - [Photographs of convention], 1979; Series 6 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - [Photographs of convention], 1979; Series 6 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - [Photographs of convention], 1979; Series 6 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - [Photographs of convention], 1979; Series 6 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - [Photographs of convention], 1979; Series 6 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - [Photographs of convention], 1979; Series 6 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - [Photographs of convention], 1979; Series 6 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - [Photographs of convention], 1979; Series 6 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - [Photographs of convention], 1979; Series 6 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - [Photographs of convention], 1979; Series 6 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Art show, 1979; Series 6 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Banquet tables, 1979; Series 6 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Dixon, Jean, 1979; Series 6 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Kaye, Danny, 1979; Series 6 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Kuchnik, Dennis, 1979; Series 6 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Misc, 1979; Series 6 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Misc. unidentified, 1979; Series 6 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Nader, Ralph, 1979; Series 6 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - [Photographs], circa 1965-1985; Series 6 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - [Photographs], circa 1965-1985; Series 6 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - [Photographs], circa 1965-1985; Series 6 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - [Photographs], circa 1965-1985; Series 6 (Box 45, Folder 4)